A movie director is making a film
on the Tenpo famine,
and they want to film
a peasant eating grass.
A period movie!
Konta, congratulations!
-Congratulations!
-Konta! Congratulations!
Obon holidays, huh.
Shouldn't we at least visit Midori's
grandma's grave? She built this villa.
-Grandma's photo!
-I want to see it!
She was a beauty.
I found a yukata in the storage room.
Try it on.
Must be a keepsake from your grandma.
-Ta-da!
-Oh! So cute!
Summer festival?
Shall I guide you?
Wow.
Could this be…
My Grandma's?
Ms. Nobuko really loved this town.
Can I take this back with me?
It's Obon, after all.
I think Grandma would be happier
if we kept them in the villa.
This way
Grandma can return to the villa too.
I'm glad I met you, Mr. Nishigami.
I'm home, Mr. Nishigami.
-So hot! Sorry Grandma!
-Hey, careful!
Grandma, welcome back.
Grandma, I think it's about time
I find success.
So help me out!
Make The Great Tenpo Famine a hit!
Grandma, nice to meet you.
I'm Rinrin,
Midori's classmate from university.
I have been feeling
very refreshed at your villa.
Man, it really is a nice villa.
I got to enjoy my vacation
while chipping away at my savings.
We caught rainbow trout and ate them.
Sorry for taking life from this land.
Grandma,
thank you for leaving this villa behind.
I lost my job, but thanks to this villa,
I can have fun like this now.
I think we siblings made you
worry a lot, but from now on,
I will find my path
and move forward with all I have.
-All right, let's eat.
-Yeah.
Let's make an offering to Grandma too.
-All right, let's drink!
-Yeah!
-I'll make some stupid alcohol for her.
-What?
-It's fine.
-Regular alcohol is fine.
I think she would like my alcohol!
No, that gives you a hangover.
Do you want some, Grandma?
It has been a while,
Mr. Nishigami.
Why are you here?
At the end of summer,
a great flood will come,
and there will be a landslide.
Oh, dear!
So, will they all die?
They're still so young!
They haven't gotten
to live their lives yet, unlike me!
There is nothing I can do.
Please!
Can't you save them?
That is a grave violation of the rules.
If you break the rules,
what will happen to you?
It is impossible
for a Grim Reaper to break the rules.
Goodness…
Hey.
If I try to change their destiny,
will you be violating the rules
for telling me this?
I don't know.
There is no precedent.
Hey, Midori.
How was it with Mr. Nishigami?
You've been acting weird
since you came back.
Could it be you two kissed?
-No way!
-What are you talking about?
We didn't!
Then did you hold hands?
-Huh?
-What?
-Really?
-Who knows.
Hey, you girls.
This is no time to fool around.
You all must leave this place.
You'll die in the typhoon!
Did you really hold hands?
No.
Not exactly, but…
But the vibes were good, right?
What should I do?
They can't hear me.
Someone help!
Please deliver my voice to these children!
Yes, I can hear you.
-Huh?
-What?
Did it say something?
Wait.
What is this?
Hey.
Hey, help me!
Yes!
What kind of help do you need?
-The AI activated on its own?
-I wonder why?
Tell my grandchildren for me.
A message for your grandchildren?
-Yes!
-Grandchildren?
We didn't say anything, though.
-It must be broken.
-Understood.
I can repeat the sentences you say.
What do you want me to repeat?
You are all grown adults,
yet you don't even work.
You stay here every day,
drinking alcohol,
just idling around in a place like this!
You are all grown adults, yet you
don't even work, you stay here every day,
drinking alcohol, just idling around…
-Why does it know about our lives?
-So weird.
In the first place,
this villa isn't a place
for young people like you to come!
In the first place, a villa like this
isn't a place
for young people like you to come!
This is a place for people who have
achieved a certain amount of success,
and are semi-retired, to come to relax!
This is a place for people who have
achieved a certain amount of success,
and are semi-retired, to come to relax!
We want to succeed, but we can't!
It will be okay!
You have The Great Tenpo Famine coming up!
Go back to Tokyo right now!
Go back to Tokyo right now.
We won't go back now!
We're on vacation!
Wow, so strict.
I see, then I need a different approach.
What did it say?
This villa
is cursed!
If you stay here,
all of you will die!
This villa is cursed.
If you stay here, all of you will die!
Because, at the end of summer…
-What?
-A blackout?
Did the breaker trip?
Konta, go check the breaker.
What is a breaker?
-What?
-And where is it?
I don't know, maybe over there?
In the hallway? Go look for it!
I'm going.
Well, it's fine.
Let's just make
a bonfire out there and drink.
No way! I'm scared when it's so dark!
-Konta, where are you? Come back!
-What's wrong, Rinrin?
I'll look for a flashlight.
-Hey!
-A flashlight?
-Oh.
-Right.
What's wrong?
-You okay?
-What?
I thought I saw your grandma's face.
Hey, cut it out. Why say that?
It looked like your grandma, Midori.
-What?
-Just like the photo.
-Cut it out, I'm scared!
-It's scary, isn't it?
Oh, it's Obon!
Grandma came to visit us!
Grandma!
Hey!
Grandma, can you hear me?
It's me, Midori.
Grandma, you know,
since coming to this villa,
I've been so happy.
I've been enjoying the summer oranges
from the garden.
I make them into juice!
Mixed with alcohol, though.
Grandma, this villa is dear to you,
so I will take care of it forever!
Mr. Nishigami is here too, so it's fine.
Next year, the year after next,
even when I become an adult…
You are an adult, though.
Even when I become a granny,
forever and ever.
So that we can all spend
our vacations at this villa together.
-Huh?
-What the heck?
What are you two doing?
I think what I did backfired.
I thought if I pretended to be a ghost,
they would be scared and stay away.
But they…
They know what I look like?
It's Obon.
They found old photos of you
and put them up around the house.
So…
I see.
That recognized me.
You didn't mention the landslide, did you?
I did!
I said it,
but that machine
didn't pick up those words.
I see.
Perhaps Lady Yomi intervened.
Hey.
Please, Mr. Nishigami.
Save those children.
They are still so young.
And they have to die just because
they came here? It's a tragedy!
When I meet them in heaven,
how do I even apologize…
I cannot do as you requested.
Wait.
Please, Mr. Nishigami. Please.
Let me talk with them!
I cannot do that.
I am relieved, Grim Reaper.
Lately, you have been playing around
with those humans almost every day,
so I was worried.
But it seems you understand
what your duties are.
Yes…
That old woman
lived out her natural lifespan,
so she was able to come back for Obon.
The lives of humans
are built around comforting
the dead at every opportunity.
To comfort the dead…
Only in death is a human complete.
With death, their lives are fulfilled.
Grandma…
Thanks to you,
I may…
be falling in love for the first time!
As the Obon holiday comes to an end,
people are rushing back
from hometowns and tourist destinations.
On expressways,
heavy congestion has been occurring
since morning, mainly on inbound lines,
with long lines of cars
even exceeding 30 to 40 kilometers.
HATO SABLÉS!
This person…
Who is this?
Thank you.
Now to our next story.
From now until the end of summer,
there will be increased risk
of powerful typhoons forming.
According to the Meteorological Agency…
Orange peels…
How do you make them?
If you want, we can make them together.
Konta. I'm going with you.
Tetsuro!
I'm going to fish for horse mackerel.
You got the first fish!
In order to survive,
you even have to eat grass!
You're interested in Midori, aren't you?
Am I?
Hey, so…
What is our relationship right now?
Your recent actions
have been unacceptable.
Falling in love with a human
is out of the question.
A typhoon is coming soon.
Those five you are so close with
will all die.
Subtitle translation by: Nix S.